oxo.com 2018-08-28

# Privacy Policy | OXO

We value the trust you place in OXO International, Ltd., a member of the Helen of Troy family of companies (referred to as "OXO" or "we" or "our"). We want to ensure that you understand what information we gather about you, how we use it, and the safeguards we have in place in order to protect it. If you have additional questions or would like further information on this topic, please feel free to contact us. OXO may update this policy from time to time. Please visit this page periodically to review the privacy policy.

### How does OXO ensure that your information is secure?

OXO will maintain practices and procedures designed to ensure the security, integrity and confidentiality of customer information. We restrict and limit access to customer information only to those of our employees or authorized service providers who need it to carry out their business functions, and educate our employees about safeguarding customer information and preventing its unauthorized access, disclosure, or use. When credit card information is transmitted online, OXO uses industry standard security measures called SSL (secure socket layer encryption).

### What type of information does OXO collect?

OXO gathers customer information needed to provide superior service, communicate offers on merchandise and services that we believe will be of interest to you, and to administer our business. In order to best serve you, we may gather information from you in a few instances.

First, when you visit our site, we may collect non-personally identifiable information from you. Through the use of computer "cookies" (small pieces of information that are stored by the browser on your hard drive), we collect data, such as your IP address, browser type, domain name, and specific OXO web pages through which you click. The cookies that are configured by us do not contain any personally identifying information, such as your name, or sensitive information, such as your credit card number. This data is collected automatically, and utilized in aggregate to help us look for trends so that we can improve our website and your OXO experience. The cookies also allow us to recognize you when you return to our site and to provide you with a customized experience that we feel will be of value to you.

Most web browsers allow you to exercise control over cookie files on your computer by erasing them, blocking them, or notifying you when such a file is stored. Please take a look at your particular browser for instructions on this function. If you do elect to disable the OXO cookie, please note that you may not be able to take full advantage of a personalized experience at OXO.

OXO also uses Google Analytics and Adwords  to compile information collected via cookies in a manner which is helpful to us in analyzing visitors' use of the OXO website. Google Analytics also uses this information to place advertisements for our products on other sites that you visit after your use of our website. These advertisements may be based upon the pages you visited during your use of our website. This information may be shared with other organizations such as advertisers and our partners, who might use it with information about how you use other websites, including to identify shared interests and behaviors across groups of users who visit our (and other) website. To learn more, visit “[How Google Uses data when you use our partner sites or apps](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).”

Users may opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browers Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). Users may opt out of third party vendor use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative Opt-out Page](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).[](file:///C:/Users/amgarcia/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/OWSWJUJB/OXO%20Privacy%20Policy%20January%202016%20V3.docx#_msocom_5)

Additionally, we may ask you to voluntarily provide personally identifiable information (PII) in a few circumstances. For example, when you purchase items, we will ask you to voluntarily provide certain PII, such as, your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit card number. We need this information to process and fulfill your order and notify you of order status. Other examples of when we may ask you to voluntarily provide PII include if you subscribe to our email program (information such as your name and e-mail address), choose to provide us preference information (such as interests, product preferences, and items purchased), or when you enter a sweepstakes or promotion (information such as name, address and telephone number).

Finally, in order to provide you with goods and services designed to meet your needs, we may collect demographic information (such as number of household members, age, and gender), purchase preference information, and mailing lists from third parties. We use this information to customize your experience on our website and to provide you with the most relevant products and services.

### What information do we share and with whom?

OXO does not rent or sell customer information to outside marketers. In certain circumstances, OXO may share your customer information with its affiliated companies.  For example, your information may be used to send you promotional materials about goods and services (including special offers and promotions) either offered by OXO or OXO’s affiliates.  OXO may also share your customer information with trusted service providers that need access to your information to provide operational or other support services. To ensure the confidentiality and security of your information, service providers must agree to safeguard your information in strict compliance with our policy. We also may provide information to regulatory authorities and law enforcement officials in accordance with applicable law or when we otherwise believe in good faith that the law requires it. In the event of a sale of all or part of one of our businesses, we may share customer information related to that business as part of the transaction.

### Does OXO collect information from my social media sites or on pages OXO has on social media sites?

Personal information may be collected directly by OXO through our Social Media Pages and may be collected by the social media site hosting the OXO Social Media Page.

Personal Information collected directly by OXO: The collection of personal information directly by OXO on our Social Media Pages will include the type of information addressed under "What type of information does OXO collect?" above. Examples of how personal information may be directly collected on OXO Social Media Pages include providing information through an application or form which has a link to this privacy policy. OXO uses the information collected on its Social Media Pages to send communications regarding our products, services, and promotions; to respond to your inquiries; to conduct surveys, sweepstakes or contests; to analyze your activity on our Social Media Pages and to develop our products and services.

Personal Information collected by the social media sites: This privacy policy does not cover the privacy and security practices of the social media sites on which OXO has Social Media Pages. Please review privacy policies and terms of service on the social media sites if you have any questions about their privacy or security practices.

The social media sites where OXO has Social Media Pages may provide aggregate information and analysis to OXO about your use of our Social Media Pages. This allows us to better understand and analyze our user growth, general demographic information about the users of our Social Media Pages, and interaction with content on our Social Media Pages. Overall, this information may be used to help us understand the types of visitors and users of our Social Media Pages and use of the content.

### **How does OXO use the information it collects?**

In addition to the uses described in the above sections, OXO may use the information to fulfill product orders; to fulfill your requests (such as contact us, email a friend or shipping updates,); to contact you or the product recipient(s) in the event of order or delivery difficulties; to serve site content; to provide marketing communications regarding our products, services and promotions to you (including sending cart abandonment emails) and to people in your account; to analyze your activity with us, including interaction with our Websites, the effectiveness of our advertising and your purchases; to personalize our communications to you; to respond to your inquiries; to update information maintained in your online profile; to conduct surveys, sweepstakes or contests; and to develop our products, services, and Websites. We may also use the information that we collect under this Privacy Policy for the purpose of providing personalized content across different Internet browsers or devices that you use to access our Websites and mobile applications.

### What is OXO's commitment to children's privacy?

Protecting the privacy of the young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.

### Can I "opt out" of receiving promotional e-mails from OXO?

OXO may send you e-mails with promotional offers. If you would no longer like to receive e-mailed special event information, sales notifications or other messages from OXO, you may contact us and your e-mail address will be removed from our marketing list.

### How can I access my OXO information obtained through this website?

You can access your OXO information obtained through this website by contacting us.

### **Does OXO update its Privacy Policy?   **

As we continue to offer you new and different types of content and services, we may modify our information collection, use, or disclosure practices.  Should there be a material change to our information collection, use or disclosure practices, it will be applied only to information collected on a going forward basis, and we will update this privacy policy statement.

### **Who can I contact if I have a question about OXO’s Privacy Policy?**

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding our privacy practices, please email us at [Marketing@oxo.com](mailto:Marketing@oxo.com) or write to us at the following address:

Attn: OXO Brand Communications Team

OXO International

601 West 26th Street, Suite 1050

New York, NY 10001

This policy was last updated April 2016.

All website design, graphics, text selections arrangement, and software are Copyright 2004, OXO International, Ltd. All rights reserved.
